## **Pedro Vieira**

UX Designer / Graphic Designer

linkedin.com/in/pedro-vieira-design (+351) 964 399 343 Online Portfolio vieira.dg@gmail.com

## **About**

UX designer, passionate about creativity and sustainable design, with a background in graphic design.

Resourceful and creative problem solver, experienced in design thinking processes. Helped teams run through design cycles to explore, create and deliver user-focused, value-driven concepts for brands and products.

### Skills

- User-Centered Design
- Design Thinking
- Competitive Analysis
- User Research
- User Personas
- Information Architecture
- User Flows
- Iterative Wireframing and Prototyping
- Usability and Preference Testing
- Language Systems and Styleguides
- HTML and CSS Fundamentals

#### Tools

- Figma
- Miro
- Illustrator
- Figjam
- Photoshop
- After effects

# Education

#### CareerFoundry

User Experience Design, UX Certification Intensive project-based mentored training program Mar 2022

#### **IADE - Creative University**

Postgraduate, Design Thinking & Prototyping Jul 2017

#### **Polytechnic Institute of Castelo Branco**

Bachelor's Degree, Visual Communication Design

# Languages

Portuguese (Native)
English (Professional proficiency)

# **UX Projects**

### Viv - Health & Wellbeing app

UX/UI Designer - CareerFoundry Project

Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

- Created an inclusive, responsive health web portal designed to help people manage daily health issues.
- Conducted user research, crafted wireframes and prototypes, analyzed usability tests results and implemented users' feedback, refined designs according to accessibility principles and prepared them for dev handoff.

#### > View project <

## Speakin' - Language Learning app

UX Designer - CareerFoundry Project

Sep 2020 - Nov 2021

 Conceptualised a language learning mobile app by taking the project through design thinking stages, including competitive analysis, user research, information architecture, ideation, prototyping and user testing.

#### > View project <

# Professional Experience

### Freelance Graphic Designer

Freelancer, Portugal / Sep 2009 - Present

Worked for a diverse range of self-sourced clients,

Translated briefings into meaningful concepts and unique brand assets, resulting in strong visual identities aligned with clients' culture and business goals.

## At Mendes Gonçalves S.A. / Santarém, Portugal

### **Creative Designer - Innovation Lab.** 2

2017 - 2021

Worked Alongside a small team of food engineers facilitating workshops, conducting experiments and building prototypes, which helped stakeholders envision, test and develop new products and services aligned with a healthier, more sustainable and regenerative food system.

### **Graphic Designer - Brand Keeper**

Collaborated with a multidisciplinary team of designers, marketers and copywriters on the rebranding and implementation of what came to be one of the top-of-mind brands of its category in the Portuguese food market.

#### **Graphic Designer - Junior**

2009 - 2012

2012 - 2017

Kickstarted the design career at a food industry company.

Responsible for crafting and implementing visual identities, creating new product packaging concepts and achieving visual communication consistency across all print and digital assets helping to boost brand visibility in the market.